Two Girls Working. Two Girls Working Collection, 2002-2011: A Container List
Two Girl Working Collection, 2002-2011
2012-M173
Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute
Two Girls Working
.6 linear ft. (1+1/2 file boxes)
Publicity and other printed material about Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing, a collaborative project by Two Girls Working whose principals are Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki.
Accession number: 2012-M173
The collection of Two Girls Working was given to the Schlesinger Library in October 2012 by Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki.
Access Restrictions:
Access. Unrestricted.
BIOGRAPHY
Two Girls Working is a collaboration between two artists, Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki. Between 2001 and 2006, they traveled across the United States asking groups of women to respond to the question: What do you wear that makes you feel powerful? They talked with more than 500 women and girls, from age four to ninety-two, and from a wide range of backgrounds. What emerged was a wider dialogue about the expectations and limitations placed upon them by their affiliation with a specific gender, culture, race, class, or profession. The result was a project called Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing. The project included the interviews, exhibitions around the country, a book, and a web site.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The collection consists of postcards, posters, and other publicity and printed material about Trappings.
INVENTORY
- Contents: Postcard Description: Front image features portraits of Aylin, Jersey City; Louise, Sparta; Susan, Jersey City; and Sarah, Patchogue. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Rob Blackson and Eddie Torres Title: Bitch School; Artists Explore our Attitudes Towards Strong Women Informal Meta Title: None Place: Longwood Gallery, Bronx Council on the Arts, 965 Longwood Avenue, Bronx, NY 10459 Start Date: 1/26/2002 End Date: 3/30/2002 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Every person interviewed up until this exhibition was included in the show., 1.1.
- Contents: Flyer Description: Exhibition flyer produced by Bronx Council for the Arts. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Rob Blackson and Eddie Torres Title: Bitch School; Artists Explore our Attitudes Towards Strong Women Informal Meta Title: None Place: Longwood Gallery, Bronx Council on the Arts, 965 Longwood Avenue, Bronx, NY 10459 Start Date: 1/26/2002 End Date: 3/30/2002 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.2.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Front image: photograph of exhibition site. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Jeff Waites, Lauren Adams, and Angela Salamanca Title: LOOM2 Informal Meta Title: None Place: Pittsboro Business Center, Chatham Mills, 480 Hillsboro Street, Pittsboro, NC 27302 Start Date: 4/27/2002 End Date: 5/18/2002 Funding Notes: Other Notes: New interview sessions in Durham, NC were conducted for this exhibition. A small selection of participants was included in the exhibition. The site was formerly a clothing label factory., 1.3.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Front image: lower legs and feet of six women. Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition Curator(s): Content curated by Two Girls Working. Title: Trappings Informal Meta Title: None Place: Sussex County Community College, Building B, One College Hill, Newton, NJ 07680 Start Date: 10/19/2002 End Date: 11/23/2002 Funding Notes: Other Notes: One new interview session was conducted on the day of this exhibition opening. The exhibition opening and event were a part of the college's Women's Weekend., 1.4.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Front image: portrait of Claire with interview quote. Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition Curator(s): None. Selected by a jury who reviewed exhibition proposals. Title: Trappings Informal Meta Title: None Place: Durham Arts Council, 120 Morris Street, Durham, NC 27701 Start Date: 12/6/2002 End Date: 1/5/2003 Funding Notes: Other Notes: The exhibition opening was cancelled due to a terrible ice storm. A closing reception was hosted instead., 1.5.
- Contents: Print-out from internet Description: Description from Ricardo Miranda Zuniga's website. Also included is a photograph of the cart that broadcast the interviews. Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Curator(s): Ricardo Miranda Zuniga Title: The Public Broadcast Cart, Wireless Park Lab Days Informal Meta Title: None Place: City Hall Park, New York, NY 10171 Start Date: 9/19/2003 End Date: 9/20/2003 Funding Notes: Sponsored by NYCWireless and the Downtown Alliance with funding from Franklin Furnace's Future of the Present Fund. Other Notes: The web page of the content: www.ambriente.com/wifi/index.php. Two Girls Working were one of many artists who were presented on the Public Broadcast Cart., 1.6.
- Contents: Folded card, two copies Description: Small images of all 21 Trappings interview sessions are on the front of the card, and a key is on the back. This postcard is a calendar of upcoming exhibitions, interviews, and residencies. Event / Exhibition Type: N/A Curator(s): None. Title: N/A Informal Meta Title: Trappings Update Place: N/A, N/A, N/A Start Date: February 2004 End Date: March 2005 Funding Notes: Other Notes: This card was mailed to more than 300 people on our mailing list, including all interview session participants. The purpose was to give people a Trappings calendar, letting them know what we were planning for the year ahead. It mentions an exhibition at the Yoknapatawpha Arts Council in Oxford, MS that never came to fruition., 1.7.
- Contents: Folded card, two copies; one postcard Description: Image on front of each card: "Antidote, Fetish, Talisman", 2004. Digital Print and Audio Work Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition Curator(s): Rocio Aranda-Alvarado Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power, and Clothing. An exhibition of print, audio and video By Two Girls Working: Tiffany Ludwig + Renee Piechocki Informal Meta Title: Jersey City Place: Jersey City Museum, 350 Montgomery Street, Jersey City, NJ 07302 Start Date: 9/22/2004 End Date: 1/9/2005 Funding Notes: "This exhibition is the result of a residency with the Jersey City Museum funded by the Mid Atlantic Foundation's Artists and Communities grant." Other Notes: The folded card and the postcard both included the telephone number used to present the audio work that accompanied "Antidote, Fetish, Talisman": 201-413-0303 x 130. The folded card was sent to our mailing list. The postcard was dropped off at local coffee shops and art spaces that advertised exhibitions and events. The museum would not let us print the exhibition opening information, so we put a stamp on the front of the envelope that held the folded card. Rocio Aranda-Alvarado is a Trappings participant., 1.8.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Image on front: black and white photograph by Martin Weber. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Ariel Shanberg Title: Shifting the Political: Portraits of Power Informal Meta Title: None Place: The Center for Photography at Woodstock, 59 Tinker Street, Woodstock, NY 12498 Start Date: 11/6/2004 End Date: 12/19/2004 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.9.
- Contents: Print-out from internet Description: Event listing from Jersey City List. Describes film screening. Event / Exhibition Type: Film Screening Curator(s): Garth Kobal, a man who organized the film series at the church. Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power, And Clothing: Interviews of Women at Grace Church Van Vorst Informal Meta Title: Jersey City Place: Film at Grace, Grace Church Van Vorst, 39 Erie Street, Jersey City, NJ 07302 Start Date: 2/18/2005 End Date: 2/18/2005 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Three films were screened that night, "ProArts", "Belly Dancers", and "Grace Seniors", all created in 2004 and first exhibited at the Jersey City Museum exhibition., 1.10.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Image on front: black and white line drawing of bus, with photographic image insert of artists' prints installed Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Installation. Film Screening. Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working. Title: Trappings: Pittsburgh Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Pittsburgh Place: Pittsburgh City Buses. Melwood Screening Room, 477 Melwood Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 Start Date: 3/1/2005 End Date: 4/3/2005 Funding Notes: Sprout Fund, Pennsylvania Council on the Arts Other Notes: This postcard promoted both the public installation and video screening. The bus installation lasted from March 1-31, 2005. The screenings were on March 31st and April 3rd, 2005. The grant funding was for these public events as well as a series of interview sessions in Pittsburgh. The bus cards received national recognition from Americans for the Arts' Public Art Network 2005 Year in Review, which noted innovative and exciting public art projects., 1.11.
- Contents: Tri-Fold brochure Description: Global Women's Voices in Action Event / Exhibition Type: Artist Residency Curator(s): None. Title: Trappings Video Exhibition, Two Girls Working Lecture, Trappings Interview Sessions Informal Meta Title: None Place: Albion College, 611 East Porter Street, Albion, MI 49224-1831 Start Date: 3/13/2005 End Date: 3/16/2005 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Two Girls Working were artists in residence at Albion College for a week. This brochure detailed our events and others coordinated for Women's History month., 1.12.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Front image: "Uruj, Tasseli, Kathleen, Marilyn", 2004 Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition Curator(s): None. Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Centennial Gallery, University of Wyoming, 2111 Willett Drive, Laramie, WY 82071 Start Date: 3/22/2005 End Date: 4/9/2005 Funding Notes: UW Cultural Outreach, PACMWA/President's Advisory Committee on Minority and Women's Affairs, UW Art Department, UW Women's' Studies Program. Other Notes: Two Girls Working were artists in residence at the University of Wyoming for a week. This postcard detailed our exhibition and lecture. We also conducted interview sessions during the residency., 1.13.
- Contents: Postcard Description: Detail of a hook rug. No credit for image on front. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Maria Elena Buszek Title: Extra/Ordinary: Fiber Artists Rethinking Art and Everyday Life Informal Meta Title: None Place: The Cube at Beco, 1922 Baltimore, Kansas City, MO 64108 Start Date: 5/23/2005 End Date: 7/9/2005 Funding Notes: Other Notes: In addition to attending the opening on June 3, 2005, we conducted an interview session in Kansas City., 1.14.
- Contents: Publication, literary journal, which includes a complete set of accompanying postcards from the portfolio. Description: literary journal title: ep;phany: a literary journal. ISBN 0-9749047-0-8. Cover image is a bird. Event / Exhibition Type: Publication Curator(s): Douglas Light, Managing Editor Title: A portfolio of Trappings by Two Girls Working: Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki. Title of piece A Cross Country Exploration of Women, Power and Clothing. Informal Meta Title: None Place: Epiphany Magazine, 244 East Third Street, New York, NY 10009 Start Date: Summer 2005 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.15.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Image on front: 3 photographs: Patricia: Nashville, Crystal: Memphis, Dorchelle: Memphis. Produced by the Arts in the Airport program. Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Installation Curator(s): Caroline Carlisle Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing - The Tennessee Sessions Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Tennessee Place: Nashville International Airport Concourse C, Nashville, TN 37214 Start Date: 9/6/2005 End Date: 11/27/2005 Funding Notes: Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority's Arts at the Airport program. Other Notes:, 1.16.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Four images on front of card showing the installed artwork being seen by airport visitors. Text includes exhibition title and location. Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Installation Curator(s): Caroline Carlisle Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Tennessee Place: Nashville International Airport Concourse C, Nashville, TN 37214 Start Date: 9/1/2005 End Date: 11/27/2005 Funding Notes: Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority's Arts at the Airport program. Other Notes: This card was designed by Two Girls Working for the same exhibition as Folder #16. We wanted to have a card made after the installation to distribute nationally to our mailing list that featured photos of the show., 1.17.
- Contents: 18 page pamphlet Description: Santa Fe Art Institute's exhibition catalogue. Event / Exhibition Type: Exhibition Curator(s): Eileen Torpey Title: Clothesline: Art, Clothing, Identity Informal Meta Title: None Place: Santa Fe Arts Institute, 1600 Saint Michaels Drive, Santa Fe, NM 87505 Start Date: 10/1/2005 End Date: 11/15/2005 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Our public lecture with GuerrillaGirlsBroadBand, July 25, 2005 advertised on second to last page., 1.18.
- Contents: Poster Description: Poster to promote our lecture. Event / Exhibition Type: Lecture Curator(s): Mary Murray Title: Informal Meta Title: Place: Pratt at Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 310 Genesee Street, Utica, NY, 13502 Start Date: 10/21/2005 End Date: 10/21/2005 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.19.
- Contents: Postcard, one copy. Description: Front image: detail of Sleeves by Deanna Dikeman. Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibtion Curator(s): Kathy Aaron Dowell Title: Trappings Informal Meta Title: None Place: Society for Contemporary Photography,520 Avenida Cesar E Chavez, Kansas City, MO 64108 Start Date: 1/2006 End Date: 2/18/2006 Funding Notes: Other Notes: This is the only known card in our possession for this exhibition. Our installation was a video installation. It is one of the rare occasions that we did not travel to install the work., 1.20.
- Contents: Newspaper Description: The Bell Buckle Echo, front page article Event / Exhibition Type: Exhibition Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working. Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing - The Tennessee Sessions Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Tennessee Place: Bedford County Arts Council, The Fly Arts Center, 204 South Main Street, Shelbyville, TN 37160 Start Date: 3/9/2006 End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes: This was the first time we traveled an exhibition and was paid for it. The show from Nashville International Airport was rented by the Bedford County Arts Council. We installed the exhibition. Renting the exhibition became the model for our national, traveling exhibition. We included this article in this section of the archive since no other exhibition materials exist., 1.21.
- Contents: Publication, photography journal, two copies. Description: Photography Quarterly #94, Women Seeing Women issue Event / Exhibition Type: Publication Curator(s): Ariel Shanberg Title: A twin-gatefold portfolio by Two Girls Working. Titled Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing. Informal Meta Title: None Place: Center for Photography at Woodstock, Woodstock, NY 12498 Start Date: Unsure. Early 2006. End Date: Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.22.
- Contents: Bi-fold, 8x10 Description: Exhibition brochure. Cover is white with exhibition title and artist credit Event / Exhibition Type: Launch of National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): Jennifer L. Strayer Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Regina Gouger Miller Gallery, Carnegie Mellon University, 5000 Forbes Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 Start Date: 7/7/2006 End Date: 8/11/2006 Funding Notes: The Pittsburgh Foundation and The Heinz Endowments. Other Notes: This bi-fold promotes the first two travelling exhibition sites: Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA and Central Wyoming College, Riverton, WY., 1.23.
- Contents: Poster, two copies. Description: Poster. Folded. Orange line-drawing silhouettes, photographs of interview sessions, and portraits. Event / Exhibition Type: Launch of National Travelling Exhibition Curator(s): Jennifer L. Strayer Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Regina Gouger Miller Gallery, Carnegie Mellon University, 5000 Forbes Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15213 Start Date: 7/7/2006 End Date: 8/11/2006 Funding Notes: The Pittsburgh Foundation and The Heinz Endowments. Other Notes:, 1.24.
- Contents: Postcards, three copies Description: Front image: black and white Riverton street scene with color photographic prints of the artists' works inserted into storefront windows. Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation and national traveling exhibition Curator(s): Nita Kehoe-Gadway Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Robert A. Peck Gallery, Central Wyoming College, 2660 Peck Avenue, Riverton, WY 82501 Start Date: 11/1/2006 End Date: 12/13/2006 Funding Notes: Other Notes: Nita Kehoe-Gadway is a Trappings participant., 1.25.
- Contents: Bi-fold, 8x10 Description: Cover is white with exhibition title and artist credit Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): Nita Kehoe-Gadway Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Robert A. Peck Gallery, Central Wyoming College, 2660 Peck Avenue, Riverton, WY 82501 Start Date: 10/30/2006 End Date: 12/13/2006 Funding Notes: Funded in part by an award from the National Endowment for the Arts. Other Notes: This bi-fold promotes the first two travelling exhibition sites: Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA and Central Wyoming College, Riverton, WY. We also conducted interview sessions during our visit., 1.26.
- Contents: Postcard, three copies. Description: Front image: installation shot of video projection at Carnegie Mellon University. The postcard promotes upcoming exhibitions and events. Event / Exhibition Type: N/A Curator(s): N/A Title: N/A Informal Meta Title: Trappings Update Place: N/A Start Date: Unknown month, 2007 End Date: 12/31/2007 Funding Notes: Other Notes:, 1.27.
- Contents: Postcard, 2 copies Description: Front image: white silhouette of a flower on a black background. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Claudia Sbrissa Title: From the Inside Out: Feminist Art Then Now Informal Meta Title: None Place: St. John's University, Dr. M. T. Geoffrey Yeh Art Gallery, 8000 Utopia Parkway, Queens, NY 11439 Start Date: 2/22/2007 End Date: 4/21/2007 Funding Notes: Queens Council on the Arts and The Feminist Art Project. Other Notes:, 1.28.
- Contents: Exhibition Catalog Description: 37 page booklet, stapled binding. Artists' work on page 20. Image of 5 portraits installed. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Claudia Sbrissa Title: From the Inside Out: Feminist Art Then Now Informal Meta Title: None Place: St. John's University, Dr. M. T. Geoffrey Yeh Art Gallery, 8000 Utopia Parkway, Queens, NY 11439 Start Date: 2/22/2007 End Date: 4/21/2007 Funding Notes: Queens Council on the Arts and The Feminist Art Project. Other Notes: Includes essays by Lori Waxman and Susan Rothenberg., 1.29.
- Contents: Poster, two copies. Description: image: white silhouette of a flower on a black background, participating artists listed. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Claudia Sbrissa Title: From the Inside Out: Feminist Art Then Now Informal Meta Title: None Place: St. John's University, Dr. M. T. Geoffrey Yeh Art Gallery, 8000 Utopia Parkway, Queens, NY 11439 Start Date: 2/22/2007 End Date: 4/21/2007 Funding Notes: Queens Council on the Arts and The Feminist Art Project. Other Notes:, 1.30.
- Contents: Exhibition Marketing Catalogue Description: The marketing brochure we designed to rent our national, traveling exhibition. 23 pages, staple bound. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): N/A Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: N/A Start Date: 2/2007 End Date: Funding Notes: Self-funded. Other Notes: We designed this brochure after our meeting with the Smithsonian Institution's Traveling Exhibition Service (SITES). We used their brochures as a model. Mailed across the country to museums and galleries to seek venues for the show., 1.31.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies Description: Front image: photograph of "Transformation" installed. Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition Curator(s): Amy Gipson and Monica McMurray Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing Informal Meta Title: None Place: Historic Costume Gallery, Lela Raney Wood Hall, 6 N. College Avenue, Stephens College, Columbia, MO 65215 Start Date: 3/11/2007 End Date: 4/22/2007 Funding Notes: Stephens College, Lori Guy of Girl Boutique, Judge Leslie Schneider, and Becky McHugh with the Carlisle Collection. Other Notes: Two Girls Working were artists in residence at Stephens College for a week. This postcard detailed our exhibition. We also conducted interview sessions and class visits during the residency., 1.32.
- Contents: Brochure, folded 8x10 Description: Brochure for East Central College Art Department's exhibition schedule. Cover says "Greeting from the East Central College Art Department" Event / Exhibition Type: Two Girls Working Artist Residency Curator(s): Jill Foote-Hutton Title: Two Girls Working Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki Artist Residency Informal Meta Title: Place: East Central Gallery, East Central College, 1964 Prairie Dell Road, Union, MO 63084 Start Date: 9/17/2007 End Date: 9/21/2007 Funding Notes: East Central College Foundation. Other Notes: We were in residence for the week, conducting a public lecture and interview sessions. The residency was organized by Jill Foote-Hutton, Trappings participant., 1.33.
- Contents: Brochure, folded 8x10 Description: Brochure for East Central College Art Department's exhibition and performing arts schedule. Event / Exhibition Type: Two Girls Working Artist Residency Curator(s): Jill Foote-Hutton Title: Two Girls Working Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki Artist Residency Informal Meta Title: Place: East Central Gallery, East Central College, 1964 Prairie Dell Road, Union, MO 63084 Start Date: 9/17/2007 End Date: 9/21/2007 Funding Notes: East Central College Foundation. Other Notes: We were in residence for the week, conducting a public lecture and interview sessions. The residency was organized by Jill Foote-Hutton, Trappings participant., 1.34.
- Contents: Quad-fold exhibition catalog Description: Front image: sculpture by May Chan Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Randall Harris Title: Well Dressed Informal Meta Title: None Place: Nathan Cummings Foundation, 475 Tenth Avenue, New York, NY 10018 Start Date: 9/27/2007 End Date: 12/14/2007 Funding Notes: Rush Philanthropic Arts Foundation. Other Notes:, 1.35.
- Contents: Postcard, two copies. Description: Front image: digital print by Nick Cave. Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition Curator(s): Randall Harris Title: Well Dressed Informal Meta Title: None Place: Nathan Cummings Foundation, 475 Tenth Avenue, New York, NY 10018 Start Date: 9/27/2007 End Date: 12/14/2007 Funding Notes: Rush Philanthropic Arts Foundation. Other Notes:, 1.36.